Contact

saurabh.sharma.nitie@gmail. com

www.linkedin.com/in/ saurabhsharmanitie (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Analytics

Machine Learning

Data Science

Certifications

Learning SQL Programming
SQL for Statistics Essential Training
Advanced SQL for Data Scientists
SQL for Exploratory Data Analysis
Essential Training
Data Wrangling in R

Saurabh Sharma

ANALYTICS | NITIE | NIT | SCM | OPS Gurgaon

Summary

Experienced Analytics Manager with a demonstrated history of working in the banking industry. Skilled in Marketing Management, Operations Management, Supply Chain Optimization and Industrial Engineering. Strong professional with a bachelors in Mechanical Engineering from NIT, Srinagar and Master of Business Administration (MBA) focused in General Management from NITIE.

Experience

TransOrg Analytics Analytics Lead November 2019 - Present (10 months) Gurgaon, Haryana

Edelweiss Financial Services Analytics Manager(Digital Solutions) June 2018 - October 2019 (1 year 5 months) Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

- -Managing analytics within the Central Enterprise Analytics, delivering analytical solutions to Different SBUs under the Edelweiss Financial Services flagship.
- -Product Cross-sell prospect modelling employing XGBoost, Random Forest and other ML algorithms.
- -Performance based field personnel segmentation employing several Clustering approaches Such as K-means, DBSCAN, OPTICS etc..
- -Customer service enhancement initiative overhaul through personalised and client oriented communication segmenting clients on Risk appetite and investment horizon along with Business heuristics.
- -Client Engagement Dashboard creation: A department wide barometer to measure the Channel effectiveness as well as client sentiments helping devise & drive proactive customer retention and engagement initiatives.

RBS

2 years 11 months

Senior Analyst March 2017 - May 2018 (1 year 3 months) Gurgaon, India

- -End to end project ownership from Data Sourcing, cleansing and imputing, calculating transformations and derivations, further translation into consumable form. Having delivered with a quick turnaround time recommendations on the back of high quality analysis, across different product streams, to a multitude of Stakeholders I have been Consistently recognized for excellent problem solving and analytical skills.
- Measuring and evaluating the output of various customer Campaigns fine-tuning and streamlining the construct through suggestions and recommendations for the future versions helping drive in more incremental benefits.

Assistant Analytics Manager(Global Analytics) July 2015 - February 2017 (1 year 8 months) Delhi

- Enabled Customer Experience Management by monitoring events over the entire Customer journey by analyzing Complaints, Customer Satisfaction surveys and thereby helped driving NPS.
- Optimized Campaign Management and targeting processes through incisive Customer Analytics helping business base decisions on facts and objective data.
- Formulated Standard set of dimensions and dimensional schema to feed into the dimensional model for online analytical processing environment.

Eli Lilly and Company Summer Intern April 2014 - June 2014 (3 months) Gurgaon, India

The Purpose of the project was to provide an optimized model for logistics involving stock transfers from importing facility and a domestic manufacturing unit to other designate CFAs.

Network flow modeling approach was employed. The challenge of clustering CFAs with an aim to optimize lead times, circuit trip time and marginalizing air freight was met using Kruskal's Greedy algorithm to establish a minimum spanning tree across all the source and supply nodes.

Feeder shuttling with provisions for cross docking was made along with circuit trip route optimization through Travelling salesman Model approach.

Johnson Controls Graduate Engineer Trainee August 2011 - May 2012 (10 months)

Pune Area, India

Vendor Development & Quality Assurance

Education

National Institute of Industrial Engineering Master of Business Administration (MBA), General Management · (2013 - 2015)

National Institute of Technology, Srinagar
Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Mechanical Engineering · (2007 - 2011)